Hello friends, welcome to my channel.  I
am Aman.  Today we are going to start IC38 New Syllabus Top 50
Question Series.  All the
questions are very important and have
high chances of appearing in the exams coming in 2025-26.  There will be six to
seven videos in the series and today we are going to do its first
part.  So let's start the video.  The
first question is which among the
following is the regulator of insurance
industry in India?  Look, now this
is a simple question and this age will be asked truthfully.
Now it has been asked that you have to tell
who is the regulator of the insurance industry in India?  See
who is the regulator who controls any business
industry.  Ok?  So
you have to remember that the
regulator of the insurance industry in India
is the Insurance Regulatory and Development
Authority of India, which we
also call IRTAI in short form.  So the
right answer to this question will be second.  So
you have to remember this.  This age truth will be
asked directly.  The next question is which among the
following scenarios warrants
insurance?  Now see, in this question it has been
asked that below you have been given
scenarios in four options.  Meaning, four things have been
given and you have to tell which is that
scenario or which is that thing which
you will read and you will feel that brother,
insurance is very important
in this case.  Ok?  So look, the first option is
that the sole bread winner of the family might die
untimely.  That is, there was a sole breadwinner of a family
who suddenly
dies before his time.  Second is the person who
looses his wallet.  There is a man who
lost his wallet.  Lost wallet.  The stock
prices have fallen.  A house may
lose value due to natural wear and tear.   If
a house has become old then its value has
decreased.  So see what is that thing
which after reading or hearing makes you feel that it is
very important to have insurance in this.
So I think you all must have understood that
this is option one.  Because
you will get similar questions.
You will have to understand the thing there and
relate it and then give the answer after thinking carefully.
Because look, if someone's wallet is lost, it's
not such a big deal.   Even
if stock prices are falling, it is
not happening that much.  If a house is getting old
and its value has decreased due to natural wear and tear,
then there is
no special need for insurance in it.
But if the sole earning member of a family
dies, then the
rest of the family may have to
face a big problem.  So
in such cases, there
is a great need for insurance.  So the answer to this question is
option
one.  Which among the following is the secondary
burden of risk.  Now look, in the
previous question that we asked, they can also ask the same
question in the form of primary burden of risk.  Isn't it
?  Now the
question asked here is
what will be the secondary burden of risk?  Let's
see the options.  Business interruption cost, goods
damage cost, setting aside reserves as
provision for meeting potential losses in the
future and the last option is saying
hospitalization cost as a result of
heart attack.  So look, the secondary burden of
risk means
such a risk which will not cause us any major
trouble.  Okay, right?
We have already seen the primary burden in the last question.
But here the meaning of secondary burden of
risk is that which is at the second level.
Meaning, even if we do not do anything regarding him, even
if he faces any trouble,
we will not have to face much problem
or he will not be such a burden.  Isn't it
?  So now the secondary burden of
risk here is option three.  Because what is this
option saying?  This is
saying that we have thought
that we may incur some losses in the future
or thinking about the future,
we have kept some funds aside.  So
you can call such cases secondary burden of risk.
So this option three will be
your right
answer.  Which among the following is the method of
risk transfer.  Now see, in this question
it has been asked that if we want to transfer our risk, that is, the
risk on our life or on the property that we own, then
how can we do it, if we want to
transfer our risk to someone else, we will do it to someone else, to the
insurance company, then with the
help of which methods can they do it,
see in the options, bank FD is given,
where is insurance, where are equity shares and
where is real estate.  So, look, the right way to transfer your risk
is insurance.  If we
buy a bank FD, then the same amount of money will remain.  The
same is going to remain in shares also.  I don't know whether it will increase or not.   It
is real estate.  Now, if
we face any problem in real estate, then
we cannot sell our property immediately.
But insurance
protects us from sudden troubles and is the
best way of risk transfer.  So,
option two will be your right
answer.  Which of the below insurance scheme
is sponsored by the government.  I want to tell you
that names of some schemes are given below.
You have to tell which scheme is
sponsored by the government.
So the options are PM Jan Arogya Yojana
which is also called Ayushman Bharat.  You
all must have heard about this.  PM Crop
Insurance Scheme, PM Security Insurance Scheme and the
last option is saying all of the above.  Now
look, we can say that this question is related to
general knowledge and GK, just like we keep
listening to the news, we keep getting to know all these
things from it.  So now the
answer to this question, I think you all
know it, it will be option four i.e.
all of the above because all these three schemes are
insurance schemes and they are
sponsored by the government.  So,
option four i.e. all of the above will be your
right answer.
Insurance Works on the Principle of Dush.
You have to tell me
on what principle the insurance works?  So options include
sharing of losses,
probabilities, large numbers, randomness and the
last option is saying all of the above.  So
see what does sharing of losses mean?
When we talk about insurance, see
what are the benefits of insurance,
that everyone is getting insurance but the
loss is suffered by only a few people.
So what happens is that the person who has suffered a loss,
his loss is
also shared unknowingly by all the other people.  So, one
principle is correct,
insurance works on this.  After that comes
probability.  Probability means
possibility.
What is the probability of loss?  Isn't it?  So the possibility
of loss or damage or any problem can happen at any time.
Large numbers.   The
large number tells you how many
numbers will be incurring losses.  Meaning
all these calculations are done by insurance companies.  Then there
's randomness.  Now the
randomness is the losses that happen randomly.   Isn't it
?  So in this way we can see
that the insurance will
come according to all the four principles.  So, all of the
above will be the right answer to this question.
Now this question asks whether risk
transfer through risk cooling is called
dash.  Now I have to tell you that if we
transfer risk through risk cooling then
what is it called?  The options are savings,
investment, insurance and risk
mitigation.  So look, first understand risk cooling.
Now as you can see, all these people have got
themselves insured.
This is okay?  From where?
From the insurance company.  Now, what happens is that
many people get insurance
but the mishap happens with only a few percent of
people.  Okay, right?  So
all these people who got
themselves insured from the insurance company,
first of all they transferred their risk to this insurance company.
Ok?  And how did you do it?
How is this happening?  By cooling.
What does pool mean?  You have to collect it, right?  So
all of them collect their risk
at one place through risk cooling and that place
is the insurance company where they have
transferred their risk through risk cooling in a way.  Okay, right
?  Now what is it that the question now asks about
risk transfer through risk
cooling?  So do you know the answer, what will be the answer to this
?  Insurance.  Also,
you should understand one more thing from here that
they also ask this question in this way that
sharing of losses.  Okay, right?  Meaning
sharing of losses through risk cooling.  So
now all these people now like let's say this
person is Joe, right?
Something wrong happens to this person and the
company gives the claim
to his family or to him, so now the claim
money comes from this pool only.
So that means that all these
people are, in a way, sharing in the compensation that is being given to him.  Isn't it
?
So risk transfer through risk cooling can also be
called or sharing of losses
through insurance.  It's the same thing.  Isn't it?  So
now the right answer to this question is
insurance.  And I think you understand this concept
now.  The
next question asks what
measures to reduce the chances of occurrence of
risk are known as dash.  Now see that
preventing the risk from happening means prevention.  So
what can you do with that?  What will
happen with that?  Ok?  The first is risk retention,
then loss prevention, risk transfer and
risk avoidance.  So if we
prevent risk from happening, what can we avoid?  We
can avoid loss.  Isn't it?  So loss can be
prevented.  So the
right answer to this question is option
two.  The Term Risk Include.  Now look,
here in the question it has been asked that
what will be included in the term risk
?  Damage to the machinery and property
Impact on the health and life of a person
Leakage of toxic products into the
atmosphere Effect on the healthy life of the
neighbourhood.  So see, all these conditions are
representing risk only.
If our machinery or property gets damaged
or there is any impact on our life or health.  There has been
some
leakage of some toxic product into the atmosphere
and it is
affecting the healthy life in the neighbourhood.  So
all these things will represent danger i.e. risk.  So the
right answer to this question is option five.   The
next question is which of the following
intermediaries do not require
IRDA
license and approval to operate in
India.  You have to tell
which of the options given below is such an option or
intermediary which does
not require the license or approval of IRDA if
it has to work in India.  The options are
Insurance Broker, Insurance Agent, Third
Party Administrator i.e. TPF
Surveyor.   The
last option is saying all intermediaries
require IRDA license and approval.  So,
see, all these four intermediaries,
whether it is an insurance broker, an agent, a
third party administrator or a
surveyor, if they want to
work in the field of insurance in India, then a
license or approval from the Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority of India is
necessary.  Therefore, option five is the
right answer.  Which of the below
is an advantage of cash value insurance
contract?  Now, if you have written a cash value
insurance contract, then you should
not panic.  This is the same insurance.
So the question here is that
you have to tell the benefits of the insurance contract.   I have to
tell you the advantage.  Ok?  So options are given.
Return subject to coding effect
of inflation.  Meaning, the returns we get are
affected by inflation.
Accumulation is low
in earlier years.  Meaning, if there are fewer starting
years then less money is collected.
Lower years are less benefits.  And the last
option is saying that it is a secure investment.
So see, the best advantage that
we can say here about an insurance
contract is secure
investment.  Because the
money invested in insurance is secure and safe.
So option four is the right
answer.  The first insurance contract was
entered into by a European maritime
nation in 1347 to accept dash insurance
as a practice.  So, in this question
it has been asked that what was the first insurance contract signed by the European Maritime
in 1347
?  Life Vehicle Rain or
Fire?  So see, the first insurance that
happened or we can say that the first insurance
contract that happened was marine insurance,
it is also called marine insurance or
we also call it marine insurance.  When did the ships that used to
carry goods from one country to
another first
start getting insured?
In the countries of Europe in 1347.  Ok?  So
which was the first insurance that was done?  Marine Insurance
or Marine Insurance.  The correct answer to this is
option three.
Doctor Nicholas Barbon set up in 1668 the
first fire insurance company known as Dash.
Now see, in this question it has been asked
that what was the name of the first insurance company which was started by Dr. Nicholas Barbon
in 1668 AD
?  This First Fire
Insurance Company.  What is the name of the first fire
insurance company that was set up
?  Ok?  The options are Nicholas
Company, Fire Company, Fire Insurance Company
or Fire Office.  So see, its correct
answer is option four, which was the first fire
insurance company set up
in 1668 AD, its name was Fire Office and
it was done by Dr. Nicholas Barbon.
Now look, three things have become
clear to you here.  One person to
remember is Dr. Nicholas Barban.
In which year did the second one happen?  This happened in 1668.
And what was the name of the third company?  So
you can be asked questions in any of the three ways.  The
Great Fire of London in
1666 in which more than 13,000 houses were lost gave
a boost to the insurance and the
first fire insurance company called Fire
Office was started in a hurry.  Now see,
you people know the answer to this question,
its answer is option four i.e.
1668.  But from this you came to know what was the
reason behind the formation of this company.
So look what happened was that in 1666 there was the Great
Fire of London, a very terrible fire in which
around 13,000 or more houses were
burnt to ashes.  There was a lot of
loss and because of this the insurance field,
we can say the insurance business got a
boost and the first fire
insurance company which was
set up by Doctor Nicholas, we have just read,
its name was Fire Office, it was started, so
see when the fire broke out in 1666 and two
years after that i.e. in 1668 this company was
started, so option four is the
right answer.
By transferring risk to the insured, it becomes
possible.  Now see, if we
transfer our risk to the insurance.
What this means is that we got our
insurance done.  Okay, right?  So what will be
possible?  See, what is possible when we get insurance
?   It is
possible that we enjoy peace
of mind and can do our work very well
without tension.  Peace of mind
means we will remain calm.  Our mind will remain
calm.  We will enjoy mental peace
and will be able to do our work easily in a tension-free way.
So you can also call this a benefit
of insurance.  The origin of modern insurance business
can be traced to.  I want to tell you where the
modern insurance business
started from.  Ok
?  So you can call it modern insurance business
or you can say that in the official way,
where did the insurance business start in the world?
So the right answer to this is option two.
Lloyd's is a coffee house in London,
England.  From there the modern
insurance business started.  So
Lloyds you have to remember.  Lloyd's Coffee
House was the name of this place.  So option two is
your right answer.
Which of the following terms matches
closest with the family floater?  Now see,
when the word family floater comes, you have to
tell which term will
match the most.  Health Insurance,
Property Insurance, Accidental Injuries,
Consequential Losses.  So,
you have understood from family floater that
it is related to health insurance only.
No family is to be included in the property insurance.  Isn't it
?  Not even in accidental injuries
nor in consequential losses.  Because all
these three come under different types of general
insurance.  It comes in categories.
Health
insurance is also like general insurance.
But its category is different, right?  So, with
whom does the family of the other world match?  From health insurance.  Because
generally when we get health insurance, we get it done for the
entire family, so
we also call it family frontler health insurance.
In cases where the life insurance agent
collects the premium from the policy holder
and remits it to the insurance office, he is
acting as an agent of DASH.  Now look,
in this question it has been asked that when a
life insurance agent
collects premium from his policy holders
and then deposits it in the insurance office, then
whose agent does he
work as?  Isn't it?  Of IRDA,
of the insurance company, of the policy holder or of the
general public.  So see, the
insurance agent represents
his insurance company.  So he
works as an agent for an insurance company.  Because suppose
if you are an agent of LIC then you
will represent LIC or if you
are an agent of any private insurance company then
you will represent that particular agency company.
So the agent
represents his particular company, the insurance company.
A policy where the policy holder makes one
time payment of the premium is known as.  Now
see, in this question it has been asked that
if there is a policy holder and he is making one
time premium payment, that is, he will
pay the premium only once, then
what will you call such a policy?  So look, it is a simple thing that
if we are paying the premium in one go, that is, we are
paying the premium only once,
then what will we call that policy?   It will be
called single premium policy only, right,
because look, it will not be called money back,
neither will it be called salary saving scheme, it will
not be called half yearly policy, so
what will you call it, it will be single premium policy,
many times such questions will come that you will
not be able to understand it at once or let's say you have not
read it, then you have to understand the question carefully,
what is it asking and then
read all the four options, what has been
asked from us, then
accordingly you have to answer it, then the
right answer to this question will come in
seconds.  The next question asks
whether in an insurance context risk
retention indicates a situation where dash.  Now
look, in this question we are asking that
if we understand in the language of insurance, then
which situation will risk retention
represent, indicate or
show?  So first of all you should understand
that risk retention means
management of risk i.e. managing the risk.
Meaning, if we know that this thing can be
dangerous, then how should we
manage it.  Isn't it?  So that is called risk retention.  For example, suppose
we are
driving a scooter.  Isn't it?  I am going somewhere on a two wheeler.
So we know that
if we fall or face any problem, then it
is important for us to wear a helmet so that
our head, our skull, can be protected.  Isn't it
?  So what does that mean?  Risk retention
means that if we know about the risk
, we know about the danger, then
how can we avoid it, it is called risk retention.
So, now you have to find the situation among these four options
which is related
to risk retention.  So,
in options there is possibility of loss and damage
is not there.  Loss producing event has
no value.  Meaning, the event that is causing the loss has
no value.  So brother,
this does not happen.  Anything that gets
damaged or lost will have value, even if
it is the smallest thing.
Property is covered by insurance.   The
property is covered by insurance.  So this is also
not related to risk retention.  The
last option is its right answer,
I will explain how it is.
Last Option is saying that one decides to
bear the risk and its effects.  Look,
what does risk retention mean?
Managing your risk.  Now, the fourth option is that there is
a person here who has said that
whatever risk or danger there is, I will bear it
and will also bear its effects.  Isn't it
?  That means he is
aware of the risks.  So that's why he will
manage the risk.  So the risk retention is
matching with your fourth option.
Therefore the correct answer will be option
four.  Which of the following statements is
true?  You have to tell which statement is
true, correct, right.  Insurance
Protects the Assets.  Meaning, insurance
protects our assets.
Insurance prevents the loss.  Meaning,
insurance prevents loss.
Insurance reduces the
possibility of loss.  This reduces the possibility of loss.
But look, these three things that we said,
insurance does not do anything like this.
What does insurance do?  Insurance Pays
When There Is Loss of Assets.  That means if there is a
loss, if there is
any mishap, then the
insurance will give us the payment in that case
so that we can avoid financial loss.
Because in the first option it is said
that protect, see
insurance does not provide any protection, it will not protect our assets, it will
not prevent the loss from happening nor will it prevent its possibility, it
just means that when the loss occurs, if the
loss occurs then if we have
taken insurance then we will get the payment for it.  So,
option four will be the right
answer.
Now comes a small numerical.
Look, if any numerical comes up then there is
no need to panic at all.  You have to
read it carefully.  Because what is the
minimum qualification they have kept for the IC 38 exam
?  10th.  So if you know some small
numerical in this then it will
not be a big deal.  There is nothing in it
except multiply and divide.  Now
read this question.  Out of 500 houses
each valued at
₹0,000, on an average five houses get burnt
every year resulting in a combined loss of
₹1 lakh.  Now look, they are saying that there is a
community.  Ok?  There is a locality where there
are 500 houses and what is the price, the value of each house
?  It is ₹00.  And on an average,
five houses get burnt every year.
Okay, right?  So now see, if the price of one house is Rs
20,000 and five houses are
burning every year, getting damaged, there is loss.  Isn't it
?  So how much was the combined loss
?  A house for 20,000.  So if we multiply it by five
, how much will it become
?  ₹1 lakh.  Ok?  What should be the
annual contribution of each homeowner to make
good this loss.  Now see, it is being asked
that how much contribution should each house owner make
every year so that this
loss can be avoided, so see,
first of all you have to see
how much loss is being incurred here, how much loss is being incurred every year, how much is the loss
₹1
lakh and how many house owners are there ₹500, now
what you have to do is distribute that loss among all the 500 houses
and how will you
distribute it, you will do it by dividing it.  Isn't it
?  So what do you have to do now?
Look, the combined loss is ₹1 lakh.  What is the number of
house owners?  There are 500.  So what will happen to
avoid the loss of everyone's annual contribution
?  Divide 1 lakh by 500.
So the
answer came out to be 200.  So if every home owner
contributes ₹200 every year, then the loss of ₹1 lakh can be
covered up.  So the
right answer to this question is option
second i.e. 200.  So even if you know
numerical questions etc., they will be of
mathematical level only.   It won't be
too difficult.  You just have to read
and understand.  The
next question is which of the
following statements is true.  You have to tell
which statement is true.  So see, the
true statement here
is the first statement and you should understand what it is
saying.  Now in this it is
written in the first statement that insurance
is the method of sharing the losses of few by
many.  That means insurance is a method
where some people suffer loss but
it is shared by many people.  Earlier also,
I explained it to you in a question
with the help of a picture.  So you have to
remember this because if you see, the
third option is written in reverse here.  It is
written here that insurance is the method
of sharing the losses of many by few.  So
many by few will not come because
some people suffer losses.  If we see,
many people get insurance but
mishaps happen with very few people.   Isn't it
?  So in the same way some
people suffer losses.  It is of a few people but it is shared by
many people.  So
remember that insurance is the method of
sharing the losses of few by
many.  In 1993 the
Dash Committee was set up to explore and
recommend changes for the development of the
industry including the reintroduction of
an element of competition.  So, see,
in this question it has been asked that in 1993,
neither a committee was formed nor the
main motive of that committee was to
develop the insurance industry further
and the new
competitors who came in 2000, the
competitors from the private sector.  Isn't it?
How to deal with them.  Ok?  So
this committee was formed in 1993 itself.  Do
you want to tell me what was the name of that committee
?  So brother, the name of that committee was Malhotra
Committee.  What did the Malhotra Committee do?
His entire process lasted for two, three, four years.
He checked everything and told us
what further improvements we should make in the insurance sector
so that it
can be expanded and developed.  So after doing
all this, Malhotra Committee
submitted its report in 98 or 99.  Ok
?  So let's assume that the right answer to this question is
option
four.  The asset loses its value on the
occurrence of certain events.  Now see, they are saying
that whatever asset it is, its value
decreases.  If any event occurs.
Event means if there is any mishappening or any
such event happens then the value of the asset gets
reduced due to it.  This chance
of loss is referred to as dash and the cause of the
risk event is known as dash.  So I want to tell you
what this chance of loss is called
?  And what will be called the cause of that risk?
Ok?  So the options
are profit loss, debit credit, risk,
parallel and primary secondary.  So, see, the
right answer is option three because
we call the chance of loss as risk.  And the cause
of risk is called parallel.  So option
three is the right answer.
Mr. Rahul Fears Loss Due to Road
Accident.  What should he do?  Now here
is Mr. Rahul.  These poor people are afraid of road
accidents.  So what should they do?
So see what should they do?  They
should get themselves insured and
also get their vehicles insured.  So,
option three will be the right
answer.
Why do insurance arrange for a survey and
inspection of the property before
acceptance of the risk?  Now see,
in this question it has been asked that
before accepting the risk of any property, or in simple words, why does the insured, that is, the insurance company,
survey or inspect any property before insuring it
?  So,
if you have to insure anything or if an
insurance company has to insure it, then it is obvious that they will do a
survey or inspection
for its rating to
check what its
value is, so the right
answer for this will be option A, that is, to assess
the risk for rating purpose, because
see what is said in the other options, to find out
how the insured purchased the
property, meaning to see
how the insurance board purchased the property
?  To find out whether other insurers have
also inspected the property.  To check whether
other insurers have also
inspected the property
to find out whether neighbouring
properties can also be insured.  Or to
see if a neighbor's property can
also be insured.  So these are
all strange options, right?  So that is why option
one i.e. survey is done for rating purpose.
Now see, whenever
you have to solve a question, you have to
read all the four options carefully first.
After that click on the correct option.
What is meant by customer lifetime
value?  I want to tell you what does customer lifetime
value mean?  Okay, right
?  So look, there are three words Customer Life
Time Value, we have to relate it as to
which statement would be correct, so look, what is the correct
statement, that is
option three because look, in the first option it is
written that sum of cost in accordance with while
servicing the customer over his
lifetime, that is, if we provide service to the customer for lifetime, then the
expenditure that we incur is given to the customer
based on the business generated, that is, the amount of
business we are generating from one customer.
We ranked it accordingly.
Some of the economic benefits that can be
achieved by building long term relationship
with the customer.  This means that if we develop and build a
good long-term relationship with a customer, the
economic benefit we get from it is
called customer lifetime value.  And
this is the correct answer.  And read the last option also.
Maximum insurance that can be
attributed to the customer.  Meaning,
how much maximum insurance can we provide to a customer
?  So brother, customer lifetime
value means option three.  So the right
answer will be option
three.  Identify the scenario where a debate
on the need of insurance is not
required.  Now look, in this question
it is said that you have to
choose that scenario or that option
where there is no need to debate for insurance.
What does debate mean?  That you will not have to follow anyone and say,
brother, get the insurance done.
Any person who needs such insurance will
come to you and say, please
insure me, so which type of
insurance will that be?  So see, in our country there is only
one insurance which is mandatory and that
is motor insurance for third party
liability, that is, the insurance of vehicles,
only this insurance is mandatory and necessary in our country,
so we have to get this only, the
rest of the insurance is your
wish, if you want to get it done or not, get it done or not, then this
question can be asked to you in a different way, so
now you understand this concept that which is the
mandatory or necessary insurance in our country
?
Consumer Protection Act 1986 on Motor Insurance S
Who Cannot Be Classified as
Consumer.  Now the question asks
that if we talk according to the Consumer Protection Act 1986, then
which person will
you not keep in the category of consumer?
Options are hires goods and services for
personal use.  It means that there is a person who is
hiring goods and services for his personal use.
Then he is a consumer.
A person who buys goods for resale
purposes.  There is a person who bought things,
what did he buy things for?
For reselling.  Ok?  Meaning to sell further.  Buy
goods and services for consideration and use them.
Meaning, this third person has
purchased the goods and taken the service but is
not using it yet.  I have kept them thinking
that yes, I will buy them and use them in future.  For example, suppose
winter is about to come.  Isn't it?
So now suppose someone is buying a sweater thinking
that yes, we will wear it when winter comes.
Okay, right?  So you can take this as an example of the third one.
and use the services of another
for consideration.  It means that it has taken the services and
yes, it has kept it and we will use it in future.  The
matter has been taken into consideration.  So
who is not a consumer in this now?  So look
who is not a consumer?  The consumer is
not the person who has purchased the goods and is
reselling them further.  So he will
not be called a consumer.  He may be a customer
but he is not a consumer.  A consumer is a
person who consumes goods or
services and when they are finished, he will
not sell them further.  Ok?  So he will be
called a consumer.  So the
right answer to this question is option two.
Which among the following is not a
characteristic of ethical behavior.  You have to
tell which of the characteristics
given below does
not reflect ethical behavior.  Now see, there is a
NOT in this question, so you have to keep in mind that
when you read the question there also, you have to check whether the
question has been asked in NOT or in
YES.  Meaning what happens a lot of times is
that you will get three things right.  You must
choose the wrong one.  Isn't it?  So this has to be kept in mind while
reading the question.  If you do
not read the word 'not' quickly, you will keep
searching for the characteristics
of ethical behavior.  But the question is
what is that one characteristic
that does not reflect ethical behavior or good behavior.
Ok?  So the option is given of
making adequate disclosure to enable the
client to make an informed decision.  This
means that you need to provide your client with enough
information to enable them to make a proper
decision.  Maintaining
confidentiality of the clients' business
and personal information.  Because see, when anyone is getting
insurance done from you, he will
give you all his information.  So what do you do?
His business and personal information has to be
kept confidential.  Placing
self-interest ahead of clients'
interest.  It means that you should
think about your own interest and benefit first and
think about the client later.  And the fourth option is saying
that placing clients' interest ahead of
self-interest.  That means whose benefit should be
thought of first?  The client's and then your own.  Isn't it
?  So look brother, options one, two and four are
representing ethical behavior.
But option three is that
people will think about their own benefit first and then what they think about later,
that is wrong behavior of the client.  So,
option three is the
right answer according to your question.
Dash is not a tangible good.  You have to tell
which of these is not a tangible good?
So first you should understand the meaning of the word tangible.
Tangible means
something which is physical, which you can touch, see or
touch. So here you have to tell
which thing is not tangible.
So the options are house insurance, mobile
phone and pair of jeans. So look, house is physical, you can
touch mobile phone also, pair of jeans
also, but insurance is
not tangible. So now you can be asked questions about not tangible
and intangible also.
Meaning, you can ask like this that
you have to tell which good is
intangible.  So that insurance will also come.
Dash is not an indicator of
service quality.  I want to tell you that when we
provide service to someone.  Isn't it?
Provide quality service.  They
provide good service.  Because
providing insurance to someone is also
a service.  Okay, right?  So now
you have to tell
which of these will not be an indicator of service quality?
No.  Ok?  Cleverness means cleverness,
reliability.  What can you say about reliability
?  Can be called reliable.  Isn't it?
Emethi means you can call Emethi goodwill.
And responsiveness became accountability.
Ok?  So now tell me which one of these will you
not be?  Its not an indicator of service quality.  Isn't it
?  Isn't it clever?   Do
n't be clever.  Be
good in service quality.  Represent ethical behavior.
So cleverness will
no longer be an indicator.  Of service quality
option one is the right
answer in India dash insurance is
mandatory.  Now you know which
insurance is mandatory in India.  Isn't it?  So
what is the right answer to this?  Option One i.e.
Motor Third Party Liability Insurance is
mandatory in India.  So in this way
they will ask questions by changing the language.  We will
ask them separately.  So you have to pay
attention to the concepts that I explain.  It is possible that the
same questions may or may not come.   It
may come, it may
not, but the concepts will
remain the same.  A customer having a complaint regarding
his insurance policy can
approach IRDAI through.  Now look at this
question here,
suppose someone is an insurance customer
and he has
some complaint with the insurance regarding his policy and
he wants to contact IRDAI.   If he
wants to complain, how will he do it?
Through whom will he do it?  I mean to say.  Ok?
So brother, whatever complaint will be made in IRDA,
it will be done through IGMS.  Ok?
IGMS stands for Integrated
Grievance Management System.  So if you want to
contact or approach IRDA, then you can
approach through IGMS
regarding any insurance policy related
complaint.  Consumer Protection Act Deals
With.  Now I have to tell you what the Consumer
Protection Act deals with
?  So see, in the options there is complaint
against insurance company, complaint
against shopkeeper, complaint against brand, whatever it is
or whatever we are taking, we are
taking insurance or buying something from the shopkeeper
, buying something from the brand.
So brother, we are consumers in everything.
So all the complaints that can be made can be made
against it.  If there is a problem
then the Consumer Protection Act will deal with everyone.
Option four is the correct answer.
Now you have to remember that if
the value of the compensation claim is up to ₹50 lakh then the
complaint will be filed in the District Forum or
its case will be heard in the District Forum.  Will go.
If the complaint is worth
₹ lakh to ₹ crore, then the
hearing or handling of the case will be done
in the State Commission and if it is ₹ 2
crore or above, then the case will
go to the National Commission.  So see, the
present values ​​are given here.
Okay, right?  But whenever, suppose today or
after a few years or after some time, you
watch this video, then please check
such values ​​with present figures once
on Google or any other source
because these values ​​keep
changing as per the government rules.
Presently these are correct values.
Select the correct statement.  You have to
select the correct statement.  The
first option in the options says that ethical
behavior is impossible if
you want to sell insurance.  The second option is saying
that ethical behavior is not necessary.
Meaning, insurance agents do not need this.  The
third one is saying that ethical
behavior helps in developing trust
between agent and insured.  Meaning agent and
insured.  Who is the insured, who gets the policy
, gets the insurance done.  So
ethical behavior
develops trust between the two.
And ethical behavior is
expected from top management only.
Meaning,
you can expect ethical behavior only from the top management.
So see, correct statement
option three is in this.  Because if there is ethical behaviour
, good behaviour, then
a good trust
relationship will be built up between the agent and the insured.  So option three will be the
right answer.
Active listening involves you have to tell me
what will come in active listening?  Paying
attention to the speaker means
listening attentively to the speaker.  Giving occasional nod and
smile: A little nod and
smile in between means yes, keep giving your response.
Provide feedback whether we understand or
not.  So see, all these three
things will come under active listening
because in the fourth option, all these three things have been
written by combining them.  So, the
correct answer option will be four.
Expand the term IGMS.  So the
full form of IGMS is Integrated Grievance
Management System.  And this is the system
through which if there is any complaint, it is
called the grievance redressal mechanism.  This is basically in Hindi if you
want to contact IRDA with any complaint regarding any complaint.
So this entire system is created
which is called IGMS.  Integrated
Givens Management System.
Principle of Contribution implies that if the same
property is insured with more than one
insurance company, then see
what the Principle of Contribution says is that if there
is only one property, suppose you have a
car and you have got it insured with two different companies.
Ok?  So what will
happen?  So in the options, compensation will not be given.
Compensation paid by all insurers.   This
means you will get compensation from all the insurers.
Compensation is paid in full by all the
insurers.  She is also saying the same thing.  Isn't it
?  And the last option which is the correct option, what it
says is that compensation paid by all
insurers together but cannot exceed the
actual loss suffered.  Meaning, whatever actual
loss has occurred, that will be paid.  You
cannot get more money than what both the insurers or any number of insurers have.  This is
called the principle of contribution.
Dash Means Transfer All Rights and Remedies.
With respect to the subject matter of
insurance from the insured to the
insurer.  Look, now you have to tell what that
principal will be called or what it will be called in
which all the rights and remedies will be
transferred with respect
to the matter of insurance.  Meaning the
thing for which you have taken insurance.
With whom?  Who has the rights?  Who gave them?   The
insured gave it to the insured.
Who is the insured?  Which is insured.
And who is the insured?  Insurance company
that provides insurance.  So let me tell you
what will be the meaning of right where transfer of
rights has been done.  So brother, that is called
subrogation.  Option two is the correct
answer.  Now comes a big question.  So don't
panic.  You have to read it carefully and you will
understand what it is saying.  Mr. Shyam
who has a factory with plant machinery and
inventory worth 70 lakhs.  Now there is Mr. Shyam.
He has a factory.  There is a plant.   There
is machinery in it.  There is inventory.  Up to ₹70 lakh.
Wants to insure them with
insurance.  And he wants to get all these things insured from some insurance company.
Okay, right?  The chance that there will be
loss or damage to the factory and its
contents from fire and other insured
property is 1 out of 1,000.  So look,
they are saying that what is the chance of fire in the factory,
meaning
what is the chance of the goods lying there?  Seven out of 1000.  Okay, right
?  So what will be the probability that will be created
?  It became 0.007.  Now let us tell you
what options will be available to it?  So let's
read brother, what options can there be?  Since
the loss probability is low, he should not spend
on the insurance.  Let's say
my loss probability is low, so there is
no need to waste money on insurance.  He should purchase
insurance and focus on the business.  They say
buy insurance and quietly
concentrate on your work.  So focus on business.  He should
spare some funds to make the loss
eventually himself.  So it is said that if there is a loss then by
investing some funds one can recover it.
And he should form association of
similar industrialists and help each other
in case of loss.  And what he should do is
gather more industrialists like himself.  And if any trouble comes
then help each other.  So brother,
why do you need to get into so much trouble?
Buy insurance quietly and
continue doing your work peacefully.  So
what should he do?  You should buy your insurance
and focus on your business.
Option two will be the best option among the
available options.
Which of the below consumer grievance
redressal agencies would handle consumer
disputes amounting between 50 lakhs
and 200 lakhs.  So see, now here
in the question it has been asked that you have to
tell which Consumer Grievance Redressal Agency will handle the
complaint of any consumer which is between Rs 50 lakh and Rs 2 crore,
so the options are
District Forum, State Forum, National
Commission and Zila Parishad, I think
you know the answer to this, the option is State Commission because
see if the complaint is up to Rs 50 lakh then
District Forum, if it is from Rs 50 lakh to Rs 2 crore then
State Commission and if it is Rs 2 crore and above then
National Commission will come.  So the
right answer to this question is your option
two.  Which among the following cannot form
the basis for a valid consumer complaint.  Now
see, you have to tell what is the thing that is
not right.  If
a person wants to file a consumer complaint, then what is the thing that will
not be the basis of the consumer complaint?
Ok?  Shopkeeper charging price above
MRP: If any shopkeeper is
charging price more than MRP, then we will definitely
complain about him.  Shopkeeper not
advising the customer on best product in
category.  This means that the shopkeeper did
not advise the customer about the best product.
Ok?  Allergy warning not
provided on the drug bottle.  Meaning, the
allergy
warning was not given on the drug bottle, so a
complaint should be lodged about that too.  It is a fake product, if it gets
wrong then it will be his fault.  But
option two is that the shopkeeper did not advise us
that this thing is good, buy it.
So this cannot become the basis for a
consumer complaint.  So option two will be
your right answer.
View of the below will be the most appropriate
option for customers to lodge an insurance
policy related complaint.  Now see,
in this question it has been asked that you have to
tell which of the options given below
is such an option that if
a customer wants to
lodge a complaint related to his insurance policy, then
where should he go to lodge his complaint?
Go to the police, go to the Supreme Court,
go to the Insurance Observer or
go to the District Court.  So the
best option for that is Insurance
Observer.  Insurance Observersman is
called Insurance Ombudsman in Hindi.
It was established in 1998 and the
main motive behind creating the Insurance Observer was
this because
earlier all the cases used to go
to the consumer court.  But
because of the insurance cases, a
special
Lokpal court has been formed for them, which is
called Insuranceman.  The small cases that
remain are related to the insurance policy, that is,
small claims, mostly
for those people who do not have much money, then
they can register their insurance
policy related complaint
with Insurance and Birdsman.  There is
no fee charged there and no lawyer
is required.  By writing an application on a simple paper,
your complaint
related to insurance policy can be easily settled with the insurance and Budsman.
So option three will be the right answer.
Which of the below statement is
correct regarding territorial jurisdiction
of insurance officers?  So see,
here you have been
asked regarding the territorial jurisdiction of the insurer.
So here it is said that Insurance
Birdsman has National Jurisdiction, State
Jurisdiction, District Jurisdiction.  No.   The
fourth option is the right option because
Insurance of Birdsmen
works within specific territorial limits
and as I told you, for
small cases, small claim cases,
Insurance of
Birdsmen has a particularly important role.  So
option four will be the right answer.  If you
liked the video then
please like, share and subscribe to the channel.
Thanks for watching the video.